SINGH SAVRABH RADHEMOHAN

<u>contactsaurabhsngh@gmail.com</u> | +91 7757024828 B-201, First Avenue, Fatherwadi, Gokhiware, Vasai East – 401208

OBJECTIVE

Dedicated and efficient Associate Software Engineer with more than 1.8 year of Experience in full application development life cycle including analysis, design, development, testing and debugging. Certified in both front-end and back-end technologies. Seeking further to improve my technical skills as Software Engineer.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Flair Labs Private Limited, Mumbai (JULY 2021-PRESENT)

- Working with the IDFY team for building their KYC projects like Capture, Operator Dashboard, Reviewer Dashboard, PG Backend, & Report Services.
- Worked with React JS, TypeScript and Material UI for developing the User Interface and Node JS, Express, Phoenix & Postgress for developing the back-end of the application.
- Worked with WebSocket's, Redis, RabbitMQ, and Webhooks for handling the data throughout the applications effectively.
- Hands on experience in using third-party APIs like Analytics, Charts, SMS, and Payment Gateways.
- Used **Git** for continuous integration and development of the project.
- Awarded as "Budding Star 2021-22" for exemplary performance in July 2022.

TECHNICAL CONTENT WRITER

GeeksforGeeks, Mumbai (JULY 2021-AUG 2021)

- During this part-time internship wrote different articles in PHP
- Total of **10**+ articles has been published till now on GeeksforGeeks portal.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

- Pursuing Master of Application (MCA) from Mumbai University (IDOL) in 2021-2023.
- Passed Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA) from Rajarshi School of Management & Technology, Varanasi with 73% in 2018-21.
- Passed 12th (PCM) from Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) with 64% in 2018.
- Passed **10**th from **Maharashtra State Board of Secondary & Higher Secondary Education** with 73% in the year 2016.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages	C, C++, Java, Python
Frameworks & Libraries	React JS, Redux, Next JS, Laravel, Material UI
Technologies	Node JS, PHP, JavaScript, ECMAScript, TypeScript, jQuery, ajax
Testing Frameworks	Jest & Enzyme, Chai & Mocha, Cypress
Database	MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebase
Deployment & Version Control	cPanel, Play Store, AWS, Git, GitLab
Operating Software	Mac, Ubuntu, Windows
Others	RabbitMQ, Redis, Docker, CI/CD

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Managing multiple projects in a fast-paced, deadline driven environment.
- Good in understanding business requirements & translating into functional requirements.
- Good in organizing own work load and prioritizing tasks.
- Good in identifying technical solutions & bug fixing.

PERSONAL DETAILS

DOB	7 th June 1999
Gender	Male
Marital Status	Single
Languages	English, Hindi, Marathi, Gujarati
Hobbies	Playing Chess & Football, Sleeping

LINKS

Portfolio	https://SavrabhSngh.github.io/MyPortfolio
Published Articles	https://auth.geeksforgeeks.org/user/talktoosaurabh/articles

DECLARATION

I hereby	/ declare	that all	the a	above	mention	ed	details	are	true	to the	e best	of my	/ know	ledge	and
belief.															

Date:

Place: Mumbai Singh Savrabh Radhemohan